Welcome back. How did that go for you? Hopefully that wasn't too hard for you to do.
欢迎回来。你的工作进展如何？希望这对你来说不是太难。
Now let's look at how I implement it.
现在让我们看看我是如何实现它的。
So first, I'm going to disable the debug shape for this floor check.
因此，首先，我将禁用这个楼层检查的调试形状。
So I'm going to delete this tool.
所以我将删除这个工具。
Then I'm going to go back to my header file.
然后我将回到我的头文件。
And under the snap movement to climb both surfaces, I'm going to create a new function.
在爬上两个表面的快照运动下，我将创建一个新的函数。
This function will return a bool. I'm going to call this check has reached ledge.
这个函数将返回一个bool。我将调用这个检查已到达壁架。
And I'm going to create a function definition and paste the function under this snap movement to climb both surfaces.
我将创建一个函数定义，并把这个函数粘贴到这个快速移动爬上两个表面的下面。
So paste it in here.
所以把它粘贴在这里。
Alright, first thing I'm going to call the function trace from eye height.
好的，首先我将调用这个函数从眼睛的高度开始追踪。
So for the trace distance, I'm going to give it a hard code value of 100 units.
所以对于追踪距离，我将给它一个100单位的硬编码值。
And for the trace offset, so now simply tracing from eye height is not high enough.
对于追踪的偏移量，所以现在简单地从眼睛的高度追踪是不够的。
I'm going to give it an offset of 50 units.
我将给它一个50个单位的偏移。
So the line trace will start 50 units above the eye height.
所以线条追踪将从眼睛高度以上50个单位开始。
And I'm going to store the return result of this inside of a local variable.
我将把这个返回的结果存储在一个局部变量中。
So it's going to be an F hit result. I'm going to call this ledge hit result.
所以它将会是一个F值的结果。我将把这个称为 "壁架撞击结果"。
And the next thing that I'm going to check.
接下来我要检查的是。
So if this ledge hit result.b blocking hit is not true, then that means above the character, there isn't a climbable surface.
所以，如果这个壁架撞击结果.b阻挡撞击不是真的，那么就意味着在这个角色上面，没有一个可攀爬的表面。
In that case, I'm going to do the second line trace in here.
在这种情况下，我将在这里做第二行追踪。
So it's going to be a const F vector. I'm going to call this one walkable surface trace start.
所以它将是一个常量F向量。我将把这个称为一个可行走的表面追踪开始。
And it's going to equal to this ledge hit result dot trace end.
它将等于这个壁架撞击结果的点状追踪结束。
So this will be our new line trace start.
所以这将是我们新的线条追踪起点。
And for the new line trace end, I'm going to first create a const F vector.
对于新的线迹终点，我将首先创建一个常量F矢量。
I'm going to call this one down vector.
我将把这个称为一个向下的向量。
And it's going to equal to updated component get up vector and inverse this vector.
它将等于更新的分量，并反转这个向量。
So for the new line trace end, it's going to be another const F vector.
因此，对于新的线迹末端，它将是另一个常量F向量。
I'm going to call this walkable surface trace end.
我将把这个可行走的表面称为追踪终点。
So it's going to equal to this trace start plus the down vector multiplied with a value.
所以它将等于这个追踪的起点加上向下的矢量乘以一个值。
So here I'm going to give it a code value of 100 units.
所以在这里我打算给它一个100单位的代码值。
I think this is more than enough. All right.
我认为这已经足够了。好了。
After this line, I'm going to call the function to line trace single by object and pass in this start.
在这一行之后，我将调用函数来按对象单行追踪，并传入这个开始。
Pass in this end.
传入这个结束。
And pass in true for show debug shape.
传入 "true "表示显示调试形状。
And I'm going to store the return result of this inside of another local variable.
我将把返回的结果存储在另一个局部变量中。
So it's going to be an F hit result.
所以，它将是一个F的命中结果。
I'm going to call this one walkable surface hit result.
我将把这个称为一个可行走的表面命中结果。
Then I'm going to use another if check.
然后我将使用另一个if检查。
Here I'm simply going to check if this hit result has a blocking hit.
在这里，我将简单地检查这个命中结果是否有一个阻塞的命中。
If this is true, I'm going to return true and this function.
如果是真的，我将返回true和这个函数。
If you like to do some complicated checks in here to decide if the surface is walkable,
如果你想在这里做一些复杂的检查来决定这个表面是否可以行走、
you can use things like that product to check the surface normal.
你可以使用像那个产品一样的东西来检查表面的法线。
Or you can even check if it's parallel with a vector.
或者你甚至可以检查它是否与一个矢量平行。
You know how to do all of that.
这些你都知道怎么做。
And at the end of this function, I'm going to return false.
在这个函数的最后，我将返回false。
And I also like to enable the debug shape for this trace from eye height.
我也喜欢从眼睛的高度为这个跟踪启用调试形状。
So I'm going to go inside of it and pass in a true in here.
所以我将在其中加入一个 "true"，并将其传入。
All right. Last thing that we need to do, we need to call the function check has reached ledge.
好的。我们需要做的最后一件事是，我们需要调用检查已到达窗台的函数。
So I'm going to copy it, scroll up to this face six client under this net movement to climb the raw surfaces.
所以我将复制它，向上滚动到这个面的六个客户端，在这个净运动下爬上原始表面。
I'm going to do an if check.
我将做一个if检查。
So if this check has reached the ledge is true, I'm going to print a debug message to the screen.
所以如果这个检查已经到达窗台是真的，我就要向屏幕上打印一个调试信息。
So here I'm going to say ledge reached and give it a color of green.
所以在这里我要说的是到达壁架并给它一个绿色的颜色。
Give it a value of one for this in key.
对于这个键，给它一个1的值。
And if it's false, I'm going to print another message that says ledge not reached.
如果它是假的，我将打印另一条信息，说是没有达到壁垒。
And the color is going to be red.
颜色将是红色。
All right. That should be it.
好的。应该就是这样了。
I'm going to try to compile first.
我先试着编译一下。
I have a successful compile. I'm going to launch my editor back.
我有一个成功的编译。我将启动我的编辑器回来。
Go inside of my editor and we're going to press play and start climbing.
进入我的编辑器，我们将按下播放键，开始爬行。
And you can see this is our line trace above our head.
你可以看到这是我们头顶上的线条痕迹。
So I'm going to try to climb up to here.
所以我将尝试爬到这里。
And here it says ledge reached and we are drawing two line traces.
这里写着 "已到达壁架"，我们正在画两条线的痕迹。
Great. This is working as expected.
很好。这就像预期的那样工作。
And I'm going to climb down.
我现在要爬下去。
Here it says ledge not reached. Climb up. Ledge reached.
这里说没有到达壁架。爬上去。已到达壁架。
And when this condition is true, our character should climb up the edge.
当这个条件为真时，我们的角色应该爬上边缘。
Right now our character is inside of this idle state.
现在我们的角色处于闲置状态。
And same as the floor check, I don't want this condition to be true if we are not climbing up.
和地板检查一样，如果我们不往上爬，我不希望这个条件为真。
And that's something really easy to add.
这是很容易添加的东西。
So I'm going to go back to my code and go inside of this function and scroll down.
所以我将回到我的代码中，进入这个函数并向下滚动。
So if we have a blocking head for the walkable surfaces and this get unrotated climb velocity dot z is greater than 10 units.
所以，如果我们有一个可行走表面的阻挡头，并且这个得到未旋转的爬升速度点z大于10单位。
If both of these conditions are true, then we should climb up.
如果这两个条件都是真的，那么我们就应该爬上去。
All right. I'm going to quickly save all, use the hotkeys and then trigger live coding.
好的。我将快速保存所有，使用热键，然后触发实时编码。
All right. Live coding succeeded.
好的。实时编码成功了。
I'm going to press play again and try to climb up.
我将再次按下播放键并尝试爬上去。
So here it says ledge not reached.
在这里，它说没有到达窗台。
And for a single frame there it says ledge reached.
有一帧显示已到达壁架。
And if we are inside of this idle state, it says ledge not reached.
如果我们在这个空闲的状态下，它说没有到达壁架。
Great. This is working as expected.
很好。这是按预期工作的。
What was your solution like? Was yours similar to mine or did you come up with a much better one?
你的解决方案是怎样的？你的方案和我的相似吗？还是你想出了一个更好的方案？
Do share your solution in the Discord channel and I'll see you in the next lecture.
请在 Discord 频道中分享你的解决方案，我们将在下一次讲座中见。